A Guide to the Governor J. Lindsay Almond, Jr., Executive records, 1958-1962
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Governor J. Lindsay Almond, Jr., Executive records, 1958-1962
The Library of Virginia
26230
94.5 cu. ft. (187 boxes)
Virginia. Governor (1958-1962: Almond)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Office of the Governor, 1964 July 29.
Biographical Information
James Lindsay Almond was born in Charlottesville, Va., on 15 June 1898. He became active in politics in 1925, campaigning for Harry Flood Byrd. Before being elected governor in 1957, Almond served briefly in the United States House of Representatives and as Attorney General for the state of Virginia. He died in Richmond on 14 April 1986.
Scope and Content
The Executive Papers of Governor J. Lindsay Almond, Jr. are housed in 187 boxes. The collection is arranged into six (6) series. Series have been designated for: I. State Government. II. General Correspondence. III. Federal Government. IV. Extraditions. V. Judicial. VI. Miscellaneous. These records include applications, appointments, correspondence, executive orders, extraditions, invitations, minutes, proclamations, recommendations, reports, and speeches. These records document the gubernatorial administration of J. Lindsay Almond, Jr., from 11 January 1958 to 13 January 1962.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. State Government
Series II. General Correspondence
Series III. Federal Government
Series IV. Extradition
Series V. Judicial
Series VI. Miscellaneous
Contents List
- Series I: State Government, 1958-1962., Extent: 40 cu. ft. [78 boxes]. (Box 1-78)
  The State Government records are housed in 78 boxes and are arranged alphabetically by agency or subject. Subjects include: Alcoholic Beverage Control Board, Boards, Commissions (including Commission on the Aging, Art Commission, Chesapeake Bay Tunnel Commission, and Commission on Redistricting), Department of Conservation and Development (including Virginia Conservation Commission), Virginia Corporation Commission, Education (Advisory Committee on School Construction, State Board of Education, Protest - Closing Schools 1960, Pupil Transportation, Superintendent of Public Instruction, colleges and universities, and Pupil Placement Board), Governor's Office, Grounds and Buildings, Department of Health, Department of Highways, Department of Mental Hygiene and Hospitals (includes mental hospitals), Military Affairs (Adjutant General), Retirement (Virginia Retirement System), State Police, Taxation, Unemployment Compensation Commission, Virginia Ports Authority, and Department of Welfare and Institutions (Corrections, Penitentiary, and Parole Board).
  - Agriculture and Immigration, Dept. of (Box 1)
  - Agriculture and Immigration, Dept. of, Atlantic Rural Exposition State Fair (Box 1)
  - Agriculture and Immigration, Dept. of, Research and Education Commission (Box 1)
  - Agriculture and Immigration, Dept. of, Board of (Box 1)
  - Agriculture and Immigration, Dept. of, Commissioner (Box 1)
  - Agriculture and Immigration, Dept. of, State Certified Seed Commission (Box 1)
  - Alcoholic Beverage Control Board, Board, 1958-1961 (Box 2)
  - Alcoholic Beverage Control Board, Quarterly Reports (Box 2)
  - Alcoholic Beverage Control Board, Whiskey (Box 2)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts (Box 3)
  - Boards, Architects, Engineers, and Surveyors (Box 3)
  - Boards, Compensation Board (Box 3)
  - Boards, Contractors (Box 3)
  - Boards, Dental Examiners (Box 3)
  - Boards, Elections (Box 3)
  - Boards, Embalmers and Funeral Directors (Box 4)
  - Boards, Board of Visitors, Gunston Hall (Box 4)
  - Boards, Librarians certification (Box 4)
  - Boards, Medical Examiners, 1958-1962 (Box 4)
  - Boards, Mine Examiners (Box 4)
  - Boards, Nurse Examiners (Box 4)
  - Boards, Optometry Examiners (Box 5)
  - Boards, Opticians (Box 5)
  - Boards, Pharmacy Examiners (Box 5)
  - Boards, Physical Therapists (Box 5)
  - Boards, Pilots (Box 5)
  - Boards, Professional and Occupational Registration (Box 5)
  - Boards, Veterinary Examiners (Box 5)
  - Boards, Richmond Produce Market Authority (Box 5)
  - Boards, Committee to Fix Salaries of Trial Justices (Box 5)
  - Boards, State Water Control Board (Box 5)
  - Budget, 1958-1960 (Box 5)
  - Budget, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Budget, Governor's Advisory Board (Box 6)
  - Budget, Briefing Session, 1960 January 8 (Box 6)
  - Budget, Capitol Hostess (Box 6)
  - Budget, Capitol Outlay (Box 6)
  - Budget, Bureau of Engineering and Maintenance (Box 6)
  - Budget, Request (Box 6)
  - Commissions, Aging, 1958-1961 (Box 6-7)
  - Commissions, Virginia Airports Authority (Box 7)
  - Commissions, Art (Box 8)
  - Commissions, Athletic (Box 8)
  - Commissions, Atlantic Marine Fisheries (Box 8)
  - Commissions, Breaks Interstate Park (Box 8)
  - Commissions, Chesapeake Bay Ferry (Box 8)
  - Commissions, Chesapeake Bay Tunnel (Box 9)
  - Commissions, Code Recodification (Box 9)
  - Commissions, Coastal Turnpike Authority (Box 9)
  - Commissions, State Commission on Local Debt (Box 9)
  - Commissions, Elizabeth River Tunnel (Box 9)
  - Commissions, Advisory Committee on Geology (Box 9)
  - Commissions, Hampton Roads Maritime Association (Box 9)
  - Commissions, Hampton Roads Sanitation Commission (Box 9)
  - Commissions, Virginia Commission of Interstate Cooperation (Box 9)
  - Commissions, Southeastern Interstate Forest Fire Committee (Box 9)
  - Commissions, James River Basin Association (Box 9)
  - Commissions, James River Dredging Project (Box 9)
  - Commissions, Merrimac Park (Box 9)
  - Commissions, State Milk Commission (Box 10)
  - Commissions, Advisory Council on Nurses Training (Box 10)
  - Commissions, Ohio River Valley Water Sanitation Compact Commission (Box 10)
  - Commissions, Interstate Commission on the Potomac River Basin (Box 10)
  - Commissions, Joint Committee on the Potomac (Box 10)
  - Commissions, Commission on Redistricting (Box 11)
  - Commissions, Roanoke River Basin Association (Box 11)
  - Commissions, Committee to Fix Salaries of Trial Justices (Box 11)
  - Commissions, Commission for Promotion of Uniform Legislation (Box 11)
  - Commissions, Virginia Beach Erosion Commission (Box 11)
  - Commissions, Virginia Bright Flue-Cured Tobacco Commission (Box 11)
  - Commissions, Virginia Fuel Commission (Box 11)
  - Commissions, Virginia Public Buildings Commission (Box 11)
  - Commissions, Virginia Public Buildings Commission, Real Estate Commission (Box 11)
  - Commissions, Virginia Public Buildings Commission, World War II Memorial Commission (Box 11)
  - Commissions, Commission on Veterans Affairs for the Visually Handicapped (Box 11)
  - Commissions, Overall Advisory Council of Handicapped Children (Box 11)
  - Commissions, Commissioner of Wrecks (Box 11)
  - Commission of Fisheries, 1958-1961 (Box 12)
  - Commission of Fisheries, Oyster Leases (Box 12)
  - Commission of Game and Inland Fisheries, 1958-1961 (Box 12)
  - Commission of Game and Inland Fisheries, Gaithright Dam (Box 12)
  - Commission of Game and Inland Fisheries, Recommendations, 1958-1962 (Box 13)
  - Commission of Game and Inland Fisheries, Virginia Fisheries Laboratory, 1958-1961 (Box 13)
  - Commission of Game and Inland Fisheries, Virginia Fisheries Laboratory, Marine Science (Box 13)
  - Virginia State Ports Authority, 1958-1961 (Box 14-16)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, Advisory Council on the Virginia Economy (Box 16)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, Barter Theatre, 1958-1961 (Box 16)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, 1960-1961 (Box 16)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, Director, 1958-1961 (Box 17)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, Industrial Development Section, 1958-1960 (Box 18)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, Industrial Development Section, 1960-1961 (Box 19)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, Minerals, Geologist, 1958-1960 (Box 19)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, Minerals, Geologist, 1961 (Box 20)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, Parks (Box 20)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, Recommendations (Box 20)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, Tourist (Box 20)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, Virginia Conservation Commission, Division of Forestry (Box 20)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, Virginia Conservation Commission, Forest Warden (Box 20)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, Virginia Conservation Commission, Soil Conservation Committee (Box 20)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, Virginia Conservation Commission, Watershed, Tennessee Valley Authority (Box 20)
  - Virginia State Planning Board (Box 21)
  - Committee on Constitutional Government, 1958-1961 (Box 21-22)
  - Committee on Public Education (Box 23)
  - Jamestown Foundation, 1958-1962 (Box 23)
  - State Soil Conservation Commission, Watersheds, 1958-1961 (Box 24)
  - Corporations, Dept. of, 1958-1959 (Box 24-25)
  - Corporations, Dept. of, 1959-1960 (Box 26)
  - Corporations, Dept. of, 1960 (Box 27-29)
  - Corporations, Dept. of, 1961 (Box 29-31)
  - Corporations, Dept. of, Civil Aeronautics (Box 32)
  - Corporations, Dept. of, Division of Aeronautics (Box 32)
  - Corporations, Dept. of, Committee on Aviation (Box 32)
  - Corporations, Dept. of, Bureau of Banking (Box 32)
  - Corporations, Dept. of, Fire Marshall (Box 32)
  - Corporations, Dept. of, Bureau of Insurance (Box 33)
  - Corporations, Dept. of, Nazi Charter (Box 33)
  - Corporations, Dept. of, Merger of Norfolk and Western (Box 33)
  - Corporations, Dept. of, Railroad mergers (Box 34)
  - Education, Dept. of, State Education Assistance Authority (HB 337) (Box 35)
  - Education, Dept. of, Board of, 1958-1962 (Box 35)
  - Education, Dept. of, Board of, Recommendations, 1958-1961 (Box 35)
  - Education, Dept. of, Education Department, 1958-1961 (Box 35)
  - Education, Dept. of, Advisory Committee on School Construction, Pendleton Act (Box 36)
  - Education, Dept. of, Advisory Research Committee on Plans and Specifications for School Buildings (Box 36)
  - Education, Dept. of, Bermuda Education System (Box 36)
  - Education, Dept. of, Charlottesville Educational Foundation (Box 36)
  - Education, Dept. of, Contributions Miscellaneous (Box 36)
  - Education, Dept. of, Driver Training in Schools (Box 36)
  - Education, Dept. of, Educational Program (Box 36)
  - Education, Dept. of, Grants Aid and Tuition (Box 36)
  - Education, Dept. of, Interposition Louisiana (Box 36)
  - Education, Dept. of, P.T.A. (Box 36)
  - Education, Dept. of, Prince Edward Educational Corporation (Box 36)
  - Education, Dept. of, Protest, Closing schools, 1960 (Box 36)
  - Education, Dept. of, Public Education, 1958-1959 (Box 37)
  - Education, Dept. of, Public Education, 1960-1961 (Box 37)
  - Education, Dept. of, Pupil Transportation (Box 37)
  - Education, Dept. of, Scholarships (Box 37)
  - Education, Dept. of, School Bonds (Box 37)
  - Education, Dept. of, School Driver Award Program (Box 37)
  - Education, Dept. of, Section 129 and 133 (Box 37)
  - Education, Dept. of, Superintendent of Public Instruction, 1958-1960 (Box 38)
  - Education, Dept. of, Superintendent of Public Instruction, 1961 (Box 39)
  - Education, Dept. of, Superintendent of Public Instruction, Recommendations, 1960 (Box 39)
  - Education, Dept. of, Teachers (Box 39)
  - Education, Dept. of, Television, Committee to Study Feasibility of (Box 39)
  - Education, Dept. of, Veterans (Box 39)
  - Education, Dept. of, Warren Company Educational Foundation (Box 39)
  - Education, Dept. of, White House Conference on School Situation (Box 39)
  - Education, Dept. of, Woodrow Wilson Rehabilitation Center (Box 39)
  - Education, Dept. of, Schools Under State Board, Virginia State College (Box 40)
  - Education, Dept. of, Schools Under State Board, Virginia State School (Hampton) (Box 40)
  - Education, Dept. of, Schools Under State Board, Virginia State College (Norfolk) (Box 40)
  - Education, Dept. of, Associated Agencies, Longwood College (Box 40)
  - Education, Dept. of, Associated Agencies, Madison College (Box 40)
  - Education, Dept. of, Associated Agencies, College of William and Mary, 1958-1960 (Box 40)
  - Education, Dept. of, Associated Agencies, College of William and Mary, 1961-1962 (Box 41)
  - Education, Dept. of, Associated Agencies, College of William and Mary, Board of Visitors, Recommendations (Box 41)
  - Education, Dept. of, Associated Agencies, College of William and Mary, Norfolk Division (Box 41)
  - Education, Dept. of, Richmond Professional Institute (Box 41)
  - Education, Dept. of, Medical College of Virginia, 1958-1960 (Box 41)
  - Education, Dept. of, Medical College of Virginia, 1961-1962 (Box 41)
  - Education, Dept. of, Medical College of Virginia, Board of Visitors (Box 41)
  - Education, Dept. of, University of Virginia, 1958-1961 (Box 42)
  - Education, Dept. of, University of Virginia, Board of Visitors, Recommendations (Box 42)
  - Education, Dept. of, University of Virginia, Clinch Valley College (Box 42)
  - Education, Dept. of, University of Virginia, Fulbright Scholarships (Box 42)
  - Education, Dept. of, University of Virginia, Hospital (Box 43)
  - Education, Dept. of, University of Virginia, George Mason College (Box 43)
  - Education, Dept. of, University of Virginia, Medical College (Box 43)
  - Education, Dept. of, University of Virginia, Northern Branch, Bowman Tract, Sunset Hills (Box 43)
  - Education, Dept. of, University of Virginia, Northern Branch, Farr (Box 43)
  - Education, Dept. of, University of Virginia, Mary Washington College (Box 43)
  - Education, Dept. of, Virginia Military Institute (Box 43)
  - Education, Dept. of, Virginia Military Institute, 1961 (Box 44)
  - Education, Dept. of, Virginia Military Institute, Board of Visitors, Recommendations, 1958-1961 (Box 44)
  - Education, Dept. of, Virginia Polytechnic Institute (Box 44)
  - Education, Dept. of, Virginia Polytechnic Institute, Board of Visitors (Box 45)
  - Education, Dept. of, Virginia Polytechnic Institute, Experiment Station (Box 45)
  - Education, Dept. of, Virginia Polytechnic Institute, Extension Division (Box 45)
  - Education, Dept. of, Virginia Polytechnic Institute, Radford (Box 45)
  - Education, Dept. of, Virginia School for Deaf and Blind (Box 45)
  - Education, Dept. of, Committee to Study Proposed Education Legislation (Box 45)
  - Education, Dept. of, State Council on Higher Education (Box 45-46)
  - Education, Dept. of, Higher Education (Clifton Forge and Lynchburg Colleges) (Box 46)
  - Education, Dept. of, Perrow Commission (Box 46)
  - Education, Dept. of, School problems, Misc. (Box 46)
  - Education, Dept. of, School problems, Arlington (Box 47)
  - Education, Dept. of, School problems, Charlottesville (Box 47)
  - Education, Dept. of, School problems, Norfolk (Box 47)
  - Education, Dept. of, School problems, Richmond (Box 47)
  - Education, Dept. of, School problems, Roanoke (Box 47)
  - Education, Dept. of, School problems, Out of state (Box 47)
  - Education, Dept. of, Pupil Placement Board, Mrs. Evan's file (Box 47)
  - Education, Dept. of, Pupil Placement Board (Box 47)
  - Education, Dept. of, Suggestions and resolutions (Box 48)
  - Education, Dept. of, Virginia Facilities Committee (Box 48)
  - Education, Dept. of, Books and pamphlets relating to Education (Box 49)
  - Finance, Dept. of, Comptroller (Box 49)
  - Finance, Dept. of, Comptroller, Chief Pension Clerk, Confederate (Box 49)
  - Finance, Dept. of, Revenue, 1957-1958 (Box 49)
  - Finance, Dept. of, Purchase and Supply, 1958-1961 (Box 49)
  - Governor's Office, Executive Mansion (Box 50)
  - Governor's Office, Mansion, Breakfast, 1960 (Box 50)
  - Governor's Office, Mansion, Reception, 1960 January 13 (Box 50)
  - Governor's Office, Mansion, Reception lists, 1960 January 13 (Box 50)
  - Governor's Office, Mansion, Reception, 1960 January 14 (Box 51)
  - Governor's Office, Mansion, Reception lists, 1960 January 14 (Box 51)
  - Governor's Office, Mansion, Social Events (Box 51)
  - Governor's Office, Mansion, Reorganization (Box 51)
  - Governor's Office, Office, Staff, Aide-de-Camp (Box 52)
  - Grounds and Buildings, Division of, Director, 1958-1962 (Box 52)
  - Health, Dept. of, Board of Health (Box 52)
  - Health, Dept. of, Bureau of Vital Statistics (Box 52)
  - Health, Dept. of, Commissioner (Box 52)
  - Health, Dept. of, Council on Health and Medical Care (Box 52)
  - Health, Dept. of, 1958-1959 (Box 52)
  - Health, Dept. of, 1960-1961 (Box 53)
  - Health, Dept. of, Chief Medical Examiner (Box 53)
  - Health, Dept. of, Advisory Hospital Council (Box 53)
  - Health, Dept. of, Sanatorium Under Jurisdiction of Board, Piedmont (Box 53)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Advertising along highways (Box 54)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Chesapeake Bay Ferry (Box 54)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Conference (Box 54)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Commissioner, 1958-1959 (Box 54)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Commissioner, 1960-1961 (Box 55)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Commissioner, Recommendations, 1958-1959 (Box 55)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Commissioner, Recommendations, 1960-1961 (Box 55)
  - Highways, Dept. of, 1958-1961 (Box 56)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Fifth District, Recommendations (Box 57)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Fredericksburg District, Recommendations (Box 57)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Federal Aid, Senator Gore's letter (Box 57)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Gasoline Tax and Taxes (Box 57)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Route #64, Honorable Luther Hodges (Box 57)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Route 64, Interstate (Box 57)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Secondary Roads (Box 58)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Old Dominion Turnpike Commission (Box 58)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Richmond Petersburg Turnpike (Box 58)
  - Industrial Commission of Virginia, 1958-1962 (Box 59)
  - Industrial Commission of Virginia, Dept. of Workmen's Compensation (Box 59)
  - Labor and Industry, Dept. of, Virginia Apprenticeship Council (Box 59)
  - Labor and Industry, Dept. of, Commissioner, 1958-1962 (Box 59)
  - Labor and Industry, Dept. of, Labor Unions, 1958-1960 (Box 59)
  - Labor and Industry, Dept. of, Mines (Box 59)
  - Labor and Industry, Dept. of, Recommendations, 1960 (Box 60)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, Commissioner, 1958-1962 (Box 60)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, Director (Box 60)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, 1958-1959 (Box 60)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, 1960-1962 (Box 61)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, Institutions Under Jurisdiction of Board, State Hospital Board, 1958-1962 (Box 61)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, Colonies, Central State Hospital (Box 62)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, Colonies, Lynchburg Training School and Hospital (Box 62)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, Hospitals, Catawba Sanatorium (Box 62)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, Hospitals, Dejarnette State Sanatorium (Box 62)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, Hospitals, Eastern State Hospital (Box 62)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, Hospitals, Southwestern State Hospital (Box 62)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, Hospitals, Western State Hospital (Box 62)
  - Merit System Council, 1961 (Box 62)
  - Military Affairs, Division of, Adjutant General, 1958 (Box 62)
  - Military Affairs, Division of, Adjutant General, 1958-1961 (Box 63)
  - Military Affairs, Division of, Adjutant General, Recommendations, 1958-1962 (Box 63)
  - Military Affairs, Division of, National Guard, 1958-1961 (Box 64)
  - Motor Vehicles, Division of, Commissioner, 1958-1959 (Box 65)
  - Motor Vehicles, Division of, Director, 1960-1961 (Box 65)
  - Motor Vehicles, Division of, Comparative Statement, 1958-1960 (Box 65)
  - Motor Vehicles, Division of, Comparative Statement, 1961 (Box 66)
  - Motor Vehicles, Division of, Licenses, Tags (Box 66)
  - Motor Vehicles, Division of, Report of Gasoline Tax Collections (Box 66)
  - Personnel, State Departments, Director, 1958-1960 (Box 66)
  - Personnel, State Departments, Director, 1961-1962 (Box 67)
  - Personnel, State Departments, Handbook (Box 67)
  - Personnel, State Departments, Salary adjustments (Box 67)
  - Police, State, Superintendent Col. C.W. Woodson, Jr., 1958-1959 (Box 67)
  - Police, State, Superintendent Col. C.W. Woodson, Jr., 1959-1961 (Box 68)
  - Police, State, Bomb threats (Box 68)
  - Police, State, Budget Exhibit (Box 68)
  - Police, State, Unmarked cars (Box 68)
  - Police, State, Governor's Highway Safety Committee, 1958-1959 (Box 68)
  - Police, State, Governor's Highway Safety Committee, 1960-1961 (Box 69)
  - Retirement, State employees (Box 69)
  - Retirement, Teachers (Box 69)
  - Secretary of the Commonwealth (Box 69)
  - Statutory Research and Drafting (Box 69)
  - Taxation, Dept. of, Commissioner, 1958 (Box 69)
  - Taxation, Dept. of, Commissioner, 1959-1961 (Box 70)
  - Taxation, Dept. of, Delinquent Section (Box 70)
  - Taxation, Dept. of, Income Tax, Virginia and Tennessee (Box 70)
  - Taxation, Dept. of, Utility Tax Assessments (Box 70)
  - Treasury, State Treasurer, Recommendations (Box 70)
  - Virginia Employment Commission, Unemployment Commission, 1958-1960 (Box 71)
  - Virginia Employment Commission, Unemployment Commission, 1961 (Box 72)
  - Virginia Employment Commission, Unemployment Commission, College Graduates (Box 72)
  - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1958-1961 (Box 72)
  - Virginia Advisory Legislative Council (Box 72)
  - Virginia State Bar, Bar Association (Box 73)
  - Virginia State Library (Box 73)
  - Welfare and Institutions, Dept. of, Board (Box 74)
  - Welfare and Institutions, Dept. of, Botetourt Road Camp (Box 74)
  - Welfare and Institutions, Dept. of, Convict Road Camp (Box 74)
  - Welfare and Institutions, Dept. of, Convict Road Force, Articles published in the Washington Post (Box 74)
  - Welfare and Institutions, Dept. of, Director, 1958-1959 (Box 74)
  - Welfare and Institutions, Dept. of, Director, 1959-1961 (Box 75)
  - Welfare and Institutions, Dept. of, Miners Situation (Box 75)
  - Welfare and Institutions, Dept. of, Protesting Convict Labor Harvesting Crops (Box 75)
  - Welfare and Institutions, Dept. of, Virginia Parole Board (Box 76)
  - Welfare and Institutions, Dept. of, Jails, Capitol Punishment (Box 76)
  - Welfare and Institutions, Dept. of, Jails, The Penitentiary, Executions (Box 76)
  - Welfare and Institutions, Dept. of, Jails, State Board of Corrections (Box 76)
  - Welfare and Institutions, Dept. of, Jails, State Convict Road Force (Box 76)
  - Welfare and Institutions, Dept. of, Major Penal Institutions, Bland Correctional Farm (Box 76)
  - Welfare and Institutions, Dept. of, Major Penal Institutions, Industrial School for Boys (Box 76)
  - Welfare and Institutions, Dept. of, Major Penal Institutions, Industrial Farm for Women (Box 76)
  - Welfare and Institutions, Dept. of, Major Penal Institutions, Southampton Farm (Box 76)
  - Welfare and Institutions, Dept. of, Major Penal Institutions, State Farm (Box 76)
  - Washington Publications (Box 77)
  - Publications and Releases (Box 78)
- Series II: General Correspondence, 1958-1962., Extent: 38 cu. ft. [75 boxes]. (Box 79-153)
  The General Correspondence are housed in 75 boxes and are arranged alphabetically by subject. Notable subjects include: Appointments with Governor, Civil Rights, Council of State Governments, Democratic Campaign, Executive Orders, Federal Legislation, General Assembly (notes on bills and Commissions), Governors of Other States, Invitations, Legal Matters, Proclamations, Requests, Segregation (including closing of schools, integration, NAACP, and re-opening schools), Southern Governor's Conference, Governor's Speeches, Statements, States Rights and Taxes.
  - Airlines (Box 79)
  - American Cancer Society (Box 79)